Guy Prochilo

About

I am a lecturer of research methods in psychology and a researcher at the Institute for Social Neuroscience (ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia). My current research is clinically focused and involves evaluating electronically-delivered health (eHealth) interventions and their effect on psychological stress and wellbeing through randomized controlled trial designs.

Contact

Email: gprochilo@isn.edu.au ORCHID: 0000-0002-1544-3694
Website: guyprochilo.com Google Scholar: Guy A. Prochilo
Twitter: twitter.com/@GuyProchilo Publons: Guy A. Prochilo

Education

2020	Ph.D. (Psychology)	University of Melbourne
	• Thesis: Organizat	ional Neuroscience with Applications to Stress
	Management	
2013	B.Sc. (Hons)	University of Queensland
2012	B.Sc. & B.Bus.Man.	University of Queensland

Employment

2020 - date	Lecturer & Unit Coordinator, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
	 Research Methods (Bachelor of Psychological Science Hons) Research Methods (Master of Clinical Psychology) Research Project (Master of Professional Psychology)
2020 - date	Researcher, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
2019 - 2020	Statistical Consultant, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
2019 - 2020	R Statistical Software Volunteer Trainer, Researcher Community Training Service, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
2013	Research Methods Tutor, UQ Business School, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia
2012	Research Intern, School of Psychology, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia (Supervisor: Dr. Hannes Zacher)

Publications

Prochilo, G. A., Costa, R. J. S., Hassed, C., Chambers, R., & Molenberghs, P. (2021). A 16-week aerobic exercise and mindfulness-based intervention on chronic psychosocial stress: A pilot and feasibility study. Pilot and Feasibility Studies, 7(1), 64. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40814-020-00751-6
Prochilo, G. A., Louis, W. R., Bode, S., Zacher, H., & Molenberghs, P. (2019). An Extended Commentary on Post-publication Peer Review in Organizational Neuroscience. Meta-Psychology, 3. https://doi.org/10.15626/MP.2018.935
Molenberghs, P., Prochilo, G., Steffens, N. K., Zacher, H., &

Molenberghs, P., **Prochilo, G.,** Steffens, N. K., Zacher, H., & Haslam, S. A. (2017). The Neuroscience of Inspirational Leadership: The Importance of Collective-Oriented Language and Shared Group Membership. *Journal of Management*, 43(7), 2168–2194. https://doi.org/10.1177/0149206314565242

Presentations and Invited Talks

2021	Prochilo, G. A. The future of science is open: three ways you can apply open science reforms to your research right now. HeSSA Open Science Symposia with Guy Prochilo, Swinburne University, Melbourne, Australia. Invited Talk. Watch Talk Here.
2020	Prochilo, G. A . Three ways you can get started with open science right now. ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia. Invited Talk.
2019	Prochilo, G. A., Louis, W., Bode, S., Zacher, H., & Molenberghs, P. Organizational Neuroscience Needs Careful and Consistent Postpublication Peer Review. Association for Interdisciplinary Metaresearch & Open Science Conference, Melbourne, Australia.
2018	Prochilo, G. A., Dominguez, J., Costa, R., & Molenberghs, P. The Effects of a 16-week Combined Aerobic Exercise and Mindfulness-based Intervention: A Pilot Study. Society for Neuroscience Annual Meeting, San Diego, United States.
2018	Prochilo, G. A., Dominguez, J., Costa, R., & Molenberghs, P. The Effects of a 16-week Combined Aerobic Exercise and Mindfulness-

based Intervention: A Pilot Study. Australasian Society for Social and

Affective Neuroscience Annual Meeting, Brisbane, Australia.

2016

Prochilo, G. A., Molenberghs, P., Steffens, NK., Zacher, H., & Haslam, SA. The Neuroscience of Inspirational Leadership: The Importance of Collective-oriented Language and Shared Group Membership. Australasian Society for Social and Affective Neuroscience Annual Meeting, Sydney, Australia.

Collaborators

- Associate Professor Pascal Molenberghs, ISN Psychology, Melbourne, Australia
- Professor Hannes Zacher, University of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany
- Dr. Ricardo Da Costa, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia
- Associate Professor Stefan Bode, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
- Professor Winnifred Louis, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia
- Dr Juan Dominguez, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia
- Associate Professor Craig Hassed, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia
- Dr. Richard Chambers, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia

Current Student Supervision

2021

Group Project: Can smartphone apps be used to reduce psychological stress in people who are currently experiencing psychological stress: a randomized controlled trial?

• Honours Students: Shuniel Turner and Najia Anjum.

Completed Student Supervision

• Total Completed: 18 Honours Students; 2 Master's Students

2021

Group Project: Can smartphone apps be used to reduce psychological stress in people who are currently experiencing psychological stress: a randomized controlled trial?

- Honours Students: Puya Pazir, Angus Panther, Tarshi Barua
- Master's Students: Oscar Goldberg

2021

Group Project: A randomized pretest-posttest waitlist-controlled trial to examine the effects of an online mindfulness-based intervention on psychological stress and wellbeing in tertiary education students.

- Honours Students: Carmen Phung Tong, Niva Perera, Dana Najmeddine, Asad Khan, Azra Mehmeti
- Master's Students: Zoe Lazaridis

2020 Group Project: The effects of an online mindfulness-based intervention on psychological stress: a randomized pretest-posttest waitlist-controlled pilot and feasibility study.

• Honours Students: Ciaran Barton, Kathryn Cianciarulo, Eman Shehata, Esma Voloder, Caroline D'Souza, Daniel Abela, Lillian Underhill, Carolina Debek, Khadijah Duarte, Mona Andalib.

Journal Reviewer

• BMC Medical Education

Awards

2019	Conference Poster Award (Top 10). Melbourne Research Bazaar	
	Conference. Researcher Community Training Service, University of	
	Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia	
2018	Melbourne Research Scholarship, University of Melbourne,	
	Melbourne, Australia.	
2017	Monash University Volunteer of the Year Award	
	(Nominated). Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.	

Professional Memberships

- Australasian Society for Behavioural Health and Medicine (ASBHM). Website.
- Association for Interdisciplinary Meta-Research and Open Science (AMOS). Website.
- Australia and New Zealand Open Research Network (ANZORN). Website.
- Society for the Improvement of Psychological Science. Website.
- The Australasian Society for Social and Affective Neuroscience. Website.